PIKACHU:
Pika!
( trumpets playing )
ANNOUNCER:
The Poké Ball,
an invention that's captured
the imagination
of people everywhere.
Thanks to its ability
to capture the most marvelous
of creatures,
Pokémon.
And to catch one
is an experience
like none other.
Each of these
spectacular species
has amazing powers
and attributes
that set them apart
from one another
in ways too numerous to list.
But unique as they are
individually,
together they make up
the incredible world
of Pokémon.
( growling )
Golem. Golem.
Geodude.
Geo. Geodude.
Haunter. Haunter. Haunter.
( growls )
Primeape.
Wingull.
Tentacool.
Magikarp. Magikarp.
Sharpedo!
Pokémon and people
like Ash Ketchum
can come together as a team.
For once they're captured
in a Poké Ball,
Pokémon bond with their human
trainers
as friends, partners, family.
On their journey of discovery,
trainers and their Pokémon
learn as much about themselves
as each other.
And they also realize
that there will always be
more Pokémon
than they could have
ever imagined.
You see, for each Pokémon
that's discovered,
there are dozens,
perhaps hundreds more
we have yet to meet.
One thing's for sure,
with each of these new Pokémon
come new possibilities,
new stories, new friendships,
and new adventures.
( upbeat theme playing )
Venusaur.
Perhaps Pokémon trainers
aren't the only ones
to seek out new species.
The Pokémon themselves seem
to have an innate curiosity
for the creatures of this world
and of worlds beyond.
After all,
we may live
on a Pokémon planet,
but nobody ever said
that it's the only one.
( dramatic theme playing )
( majestic theme playing )
( mellow theme playing )
( indistinct chattering )
Professor,
have you seen Tory?
Take a look.
YUKO:
Uh-huh.
Impossible keeping up
with him.
( laughing ):
Spheal.
Wow, it's a Spheal.
Spheal, Spheal.
Hi.
Spheal, Spheal, Spheal.
Spheal.
Spheal, Spheal.
( laughs )
Ah.
( ominous theme playing )
( roars )
( panting )
( both gasp )
( explosion )
( screaming )
( creatures murmuring )
( whimpering )
ASH:
Tory?
You're okay.
I've got you.
Thank you, Daddy.
( dramatic theme playing )
( gasps )
It's some kind of Pokémon,
isn't it?
Yes. Hmm.
It's a Pokémon from outer space.
( roars )
Rayquaza never leaves
the ozone layer.
Why now?
It regenerated.
But how's that possible?
Let's go.
It's too dangerous.
Yeah.
( roaring )
Ah!
Are you okay?
Huh?
( electricity crackling )
( roars )
Quick, follow me.
I'm right behind you.
Whoa!
Ah!
( roaring )
SPHEAL:
Spheal, Spheal, Spheal, Spheal!
( wailing )
MAN 1: Oh, what is it?
MAN 2: Look at that.
( both sigh )
( roars )
( dramatic theme playing )
( wailing )
LUND:
Rayquaza is furious.
Another Pokémon crossing
into its territory
has obviously threatened it.
Huh?
LUND:
Fire the laser.
Raise our trajectory
by 0.5.
Right.
That's the frequency.
Finally, in sync.
That means...?
Yes.
The crystal should regenerate
if we keep the laser on target.
We will succeed.
We have to.
( alarm beeping )
We overloaded the regulator.
YUKO:
It was just one small component
that malfunctioned.
A simple replacement.
LUND:
Good. We'll try again
after it's fixed.
YUKO:
Yes, sir.
Huh?
( laughs )
Guess what?
I'm gonna tell you
all about this book
I'm reading.
It's so good.
MAN 1:
Once that part's replaced,
we're almost home.
MAN 2:
Yeah, we're so close.
I was right.
I did see it glow.
( dramatic theme playing )
BOTH:
Wow!
WINGULL:
Wingull, Wingull, Wingull,
Wingull, Wingull,
Wingull!
PELIPPER:
Pelipper.
On his journey
to become a Pokémon master,
Ash Ketchum and his friends
arrive in Larousse City,
the headquarters for anything
and everything high-tech.
But he's not here
for the gadgets and gizmos.
Ash is itching for action
at the town's
famous Battle Tower.
Pelipper.
Huh?
( whimpering )
( all panting )
( panting )
( squeals )
( chattering )
( both laughing )
Yay!
Munch. Munch.
Munch.
( laughs )
Munch. Munch.
Welcome.
You are now
in Larousse City.
Welcome again.
Cool.
It's so cute.
A robot.
What could be better than that?
Pika.
Being greeted by a real live
beautiful girl
could be one thing.
Smile.
Visitor data confirmed.
Citizenship and point of origin
recorded.
These will serve
as your passports.
Our passports?
While in Larousse City,
keep them with you
at all times.
Your passports can be used
for shopping and other needs.
Don't think I'll be sending
this one home.
So I wonder which way to go
for the Battle Tower.
Pika.
Help!
Pika!
Hey, Ash,
quit messing around.
A moving sidewalk.
SID:
Dude, you're swimming upstream.
There is an easier way.
Well, if I ever get off
of this thing,
then maybe you could show it
to me!
Pika!
Nice fall.
Blaze.
Help him out, Blaziken, okay?
Blaze. Blaze.
Hey, thanks a lot.
Pikachu.
Sure, no need to thank me.
I just couldn't continue
watching you look like a fool.
What?
SID:
So I guess you're all new
in town, huh?
RAFE:
Well, if you're heading
for the Battle Tower,
you should try
going this way.
AUDREY: Be careful.
KATHRYN: Don't fall.
My name's Ash
from Pallet Town.
How'd you like to battle
with me?
Watch out,
my brother Rafe's really strong.
Blaziken too.
Blaze.
Yeah, I'd love to have
a battle with you, Ash.
Let's get together
at the Battle Tower, okay?
So we're finally gonna
settle this today, right, Rafe?
Hello, my bespectacled beauty.
I'm Brock.
Stop!
Well, I guess you could say
that your friend here
has really fallen
for Rebecca, huh?
She's a good Metagross trainer,
likes to use her laptop
for strategy.
So my name is Sid.
Blastoise is my partner.
Hi, I'm May.
And this is my brother, Max.
Hey, you're kind of cute.
Kind of?
And kind of crazy too.
Look, the Battle Tower.
Look, Pikachu,
it's right there.
I can't wait.
Pika.
ASH:
I'll be back as soon
as I'm registered.
MAX:
Okay, then we'll head
to the stands.
ASH:
See you.
There, let's hurry.
( computer beeps )
Ah.
( laughs )
Hmm. Uh-oh.
Now where are we?
Oh, wow, there's a library too.
Pika.
Excuse me.
Pika!
Hold on,
what do you running away for?
Pika.
Wait! Hold up!
Hi. Let me start that again.
We're on our way to a battle
but we don't know
how to get there.
So we're kind of lost.
Pika, Pika.
Wait, we just wanna-- Hi.
Are you ready for your battle?
Right this way, gentlemen.
But you don't understand.
If you hurry up,
you two might just make it.
But I haven't registered yet.
That will all happen
automatically.
Now, good luck, you two.
COMPUTER:
Passports confirmed.
Two youth-level participants
entered successfully.
Great, and just in time.
Pika.
Entry for participants
in the first round is closed.
Please try again next time.
What?
Now introducing
our first entry.
Pika.
Here we go.
Pikachu.
ANNOUNCER:
Our first match will be
an official
Battle Tower tag team event.
Remember to cheer
for your favorites.
Tag team, huh? Yeah.
We have Ash Ketchum
in the blue corner,
a trainer all the way
from Pallet Town.
And his tag partner Tory,
a local trainer.
All right, Tory, good luck.
I wonder how Ash
got entered so quickly.
By cutting in front of me.
Rebecca,
there comes a time
in a man's life
when he's presented with
the gift of love at first sight.
How about pain at first pull?
Not the ear.
Professor Lund,
take a look at this.
Tory?
In a Pokémon battle?
And in the red corner,
we have two trainers
from South City,
Rafe and Sid.
Hey, Ash,
you sure didn't waste any time.
Of course not,
I couldn't wait to beat you.
Hey! May!
Make sure you watch.
I'm dedicating this battle
to you.
The basic rule in all tag team
battles is teamwork.
Each trainer uses a single
Pokémon
and works with his teammate.
And now, trainers,
bring out your Pokémon.
All right. Here goes.
Here goes.
Blaze.
Blastoise.
Pikachu, I choose you.
Pika. Pikachu.
Tory, what Pokémon
are you gonna use?
No, Ash,
I don't have any Pokémon.
But...
Pika.
There seems to be a problem.
We've seen only one Pokémon
from the blue corner.
See, I was trying
to tell you.
I'm not a trainer.
I can't battle.
But this could end up
being my only chance
to battle Rafe.
Hey, I know what,
I'll loan you one of my Pokémon.
What do you say?
Come on, that'll work.
But...
Will the blue corner forfeit?
Don't let me down, Tory.
Well, if I have to.
Torkoal.
So looks like
we have our Pokémon.
Ready for a battle,
because here we go!
Let's do it.
Blaziken, use Blaze Kick now.
Blaziken.
Dodge, Pikachu.
Pika.
Go, Blastoise, Hydro Pump.
Blastoise.
Pika!
It's a dazzling combination
from the red corner.
Blastoise, Bubble Attack.
Blastoise.
Torkoal. Tory, you have to tell
Torkoal to do something.
But I don't know
what to tell it.
Blastoise, Rapid Spin.
Blastoise.
Blastoise!
Torkoal!
Blast.
( breathing heavily )
Blastoise.
Pikachu, use Thunderbolt.
Cover Torkoal.
Pikachu!
Blastoise.
Blaziken.
Blastoise, Skull Bash, go.
Blastoise.
Torkoal.
Looks like the blue corner
just can't seem to get it
together as a team.
Man, Ash's partner
isn't doing anything
to help him out at all.
I don't see how he could win.
Come on, do something.
Tory, don't worry,
I'll take care of it.
Flamethrower, Torkoal, go.
Torkoal.
Pika.
Torkoal!
Oh, a Flamethrower
from Torkoal,
but it hit Pikachu.
Torkoal, Torkoal.
How embarrassing.
So, Rafe,
wanna finish this one up?
Let's go. Blaziken, Overheat.
Blaziken!
Pika! Pika!
Pikachu, Torkoal.
And that's it.
Pikachu and Torkoal
are unable to battle.
Rafe and Sid are the winners.
Congratulations.
Blaze.
Blastoise.
( laughs )
( elevator dings )
Tory.
Daddy.
We just watched
your Pokémon battle.
I'm incredibly proud.
Don't be.
It was all an accident,
wasn't even supposed to happen.
ALL:
Huh?
Yuko, meeting you reminds me
of a time in my life
when I too spent long hours
toiling as a professor's
assistant.
I'm sure Professor Ivy
would be happy
to vouch for my work.
And I'll be happy to vouch
for his insanity.
We apologize for the mix-up
with your battle.
The truth is,
Tory is completely afraid
of Pokémon.
How could he be afraid
of Pokémon?
Well, about four years ago,
he had a very traumatic
experience
and it left him terrified
of them.
Sadly, he still hasn't managed
to get over those fears.
Wow, I shouldn't have pushed him
so hard.
But underneath it all,
I think he loves them.
All he really needs
is the chance
to get to know them,
that's all.
I'm sure that's all it'll take.
Fine. Then I'll give him
that chance.
All he needs now
is to become friends
with me and Pikachu.
Right, pal?
Pika.
I wanna help too.
So do I.
Me too.
Cool.
So, what do you say we all go
and look for Tory, okay?
ALL:
Yeah!
You're awful kind.
Thank you.
( whimpering )
( grunts )
ASH: Tory?
PIKACHU: Pika?
( both chattering )
( both squeal )
( laughs )
Later.
Pika.
( both chattering )
Munch. Munch.
Munch.
TORY:
Hey, come on out.
Where are you?
I wanna tell you
something important.
( laughs )
You'll never guess
what I just did.
I helped out a Pokémon.
Because it had its head stuck
inside a garbage can
and so I helped to get it out.
Isn't that cool?
( laughing )
( dramatic theme playing )
( both panting )
( all gasp )
Hey, what are those lights?
And I was even part
of a Pokémon battle too.
Of course, I wasn't very good,
so that part kind of stunk.
ASH:
Hey, who are you talking to?
Pika.
Hey, it's gone.
Come on, who was it?
None of your business.
Why, would it hurt
to tell me?
Stop.
Leave me alone, okay?
( grunting )
Wait a minute.
If this town
is so high-tech,
why don't they
have moving sidewalks?
Or robots
that serve hamburgers?
Yeah, keep dreaming.
( all groaning )
BOY:
I'll take a hamburger, please.
Hamburger.
Yum.
( all laugh )
ALL:
Hamburgers, please.
Passport. Passport.
Passport.
What's a passport?
Well, I have no idea
what kind of pass
he's talking about.
But, Meowth,
please stop calling me sport.
You idiot. Hamburger!
Hey, that ain't right.
Cheeseburger!
Alert. Alert. Alert.
Now, now, now!
( Meowth grunting )
JESSIE: Come on! Come on!
Come on, come on.
( Jessie screaming )
That was rude.
Maybe she takes our order?
Yeah? Well, I'm pretty good
at giving orders.
So I'm gonna have
five hamburgers well-done
and don't forget
the french fries.
Well done, it is.
( screaming )
Jessie got fried!
Without the burgers.
I think we should battle
together again.
Bet we'll get it right
next time.
Why do you keep following me?
WINGULL:
Gull. Gull. Wingull.
Ah!
Are you okay?
Pikachu?
Ah!
Pika.
Gee, thanks.
Why'd you have to go
and push me?
MAY:
Ash, stop.
Don't start something.
Okay.
Oh! Oh!
Hey, I know.
Pika.
( upbeat theme playing )
Hmm. Perfect. Dig in.
I'll go first.
Second.
Hold on.
Whoa, it's hot.
Yum.
There's nothing that can stop
an argument
better than a bunch
of full mouths.
Try some, Tory,
it's really good.
You're right.
Told you so.
( all laughing )
ASH:
Guys, look at
all those Pokémon.
SEEDOT:
Seedot.
Well, hi.
There's plenty of Pokémon food
so don't be shy.
There. Dig in, guys.
Seedot.
Seedot. Seedot. Seedot.
Tory, don't you think
they're the cutest?
Yeah.
Hey,
I bet they'd
let you pet them.
Pika.
( gasps )
( grunts )
( gasping )
Pika?
Thanks, guys. I'm sorry.
Well, we tried.
Pika.
I'm sure we'll get through
to him eventually.
Seedot. Seedot.
Oh, guys!
Munch. Munch. Munch.
( all gasp )
Oh, no, it's a Munchlax,
and they love to eat.
Well, guess
it's doing what it loves.
Hey, you,
that was our lunch.
Munch!
Munch. Munch. Munch.
Munch.
ALL:
Wow.
Hey, it's a Plusle
and Minun.
Hi, cuties.
Pika. Pika.
( both chattering )
PELIPPERS:
Pelipper. Pelipper.
MURKROWS:
Murkrow. Murkrow. Murkrow.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( explosion )
( Murkrows shouting )
( dramatic theme playing )
MAX:
There's that light
in the sky again.
Awesome.
Pika.
It's beautiful.
Well, but that's impossible.
What is?
That's called an aurora,
but it can only be seen
at the north
and the south poles.
Strange.
Well, then I guess,
we're lucky to be able
to see it here, right?
The same kind of luck
that brought you
and me together, right, babe?
Not sure what kind of luck
that was.
Hi, beautiful.
If you're looking
for a real phenomenon,
stop looking in your computer
and spend some time with me.
Okay, you leaving her alone,
that's a phenomenon.
Well, look who's still in town.
So?
Well, after
that devastating defeat
in front
of thousands of people,
I thought you might be
a little embarrassed
to show your face.
Oh, yeah?
How about a rematch tomorrow
in the Battle Tower?
No problem.
I'll beat you anytime
and anywhere.
I wouldn't count on that.
Pika.
Hey, I know you.
Tory.
Hey, you guys.
Yuko and I made these for you.
MAX:
Cool. Pokémon cookies.
KATHRYN: Cute.
AUDREY: Yummy.
ASH:
Come on out, everyone.
( Bree Sharp's "The Side
of Paradise" playing )
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la
La, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la, la ♪
( grunting )
♪ There's a place I know ♪
♪ It's always jumping ♪
♪ I'm thinking
We should go ♪
♪ And leave our worries ♪
♪ You got a friend in me ♪
♪ And I'll tell you
Something ♪
♪ This time
Could be extraordinary ♪
♪ When shadows fall
You're feeling small ♪
♪ It looks like walls
Are closing in ♪
♪ Don't be afraid ♪
♪ The dark will fade ♪
♪ Just take my hand ♪
♪ And look again ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ Is where I want to be ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ What you get
Is what you see ♪
♪ And I never thought
I'd see a place as nice ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ Forget about the pain
And doubt ♪
♪ Your happiness is overdue ♪
♪ I've been dreaming of ♪
♪ Dream ♪
♪ The skies above ♪
♪ Dancing through the stars
With you ♪
♪ Oh, take me to ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ Is where I want to be ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ What you get
Is what you see ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
When is a sandwich
more than a sandwich?
When the sandwich is a meal--
For Team Rocket to steal.
Dinner.
ALL:
Ah!
Huh?
Munch. Munch.
Did that just happen?
Munch. Munch. Munch.
It's stealing the food
we were stealing.
Oh, no, it's not.
( growls )
Munch. Munch. Munch.
JESSIE: Carry all--
( all grumbling indistinctly )
It's gone.
( ominous theme playing )
( roars )
TORY:
You know, I've never
done that before.
What?
Just playing together
with a big bunch of friends.
Really?
Yeah.
I guess it's because
I've always been
so afraid of Pokémon.
So I'm afraid to get close
to Pokémon trainers too.
Guess I've missed out on a lot.
Hmm.
That means
you're always alone.
Pika.
Pikachu.
But that's all
in the past, right?
Pika.
Hmm.
Corphish!
( screams )
It's okay.
There's no rush.
Okay.
That's Corphish.
Cor...
Pika.
...phish.
TORY:
Come on, guys, there's someone
I want you to meet.
We are we going?
Wherever it is,
I hope there's a kitchen.
( chuckles ):
I'm starving.
Your passports, please.
Verified.
My dad's lab
is right over there
so that's why there are so many
security robots all over.
Come on out.
I'm with my new friends.
Come and meet them.
Pika.
So this is your friend, Tory?
But what is it?
It's gorgeous.
And weird.
It's always here for me
whenever I call for it.
Yesterday,
I played with all these guys
and their Pokémon too.
ALL:
Wow!
Wow, Tory, that's so cool.
And it even understands
what I say.
MAY:
Is it a Pokémon?
MAX:
Not one that I've ever seen.
This is just fascinating.
What do you say
I introduce my Pokémon to it?
Go!
Blaze.
Yeah, mine too.
BOTH:
Don't forget ours.
Masquerain.
Blastoise.
Now, let me introduce mine.
Metagross.
A Metagross. Awesome.
Meta.
Pika.
( giggles )
Blast.
Blaze.
Whoa.
( all chuckling )
I got you!
Missed it.
Pika.
Pi--
Whoa!
Oh!
Pi--
( wind roaring )
( howls )
( emergency alarm beeps )
Unidentified object
approaching the building.
Can you
analyze it, please?
It appears to be a Rayquaza.
Rayquaza?
Contact Professor Lund now.
MAN: Right.
Professor, how could a Rayquaza
be coming here?
I don't know.
But for it to leave
the ozone layer again,
there must be
a powerful reason.
( computers beeping )
Do you see that?
I'll magnify it.
( suspenseful theme playing )
That's what I thought.
It's Deoxys.
( ominous theme playing )
COMPUTER:
System malfunction.
Losing regulatory control.
LUND:
Rayquaza must have come here
after sensing that Deoxys
was here as well.
If those two battle it out
in our city,
the result
will be catastrophic.
Evacuate Larousse City
immediately.
Right away, sir.
Initiating
emergency evacuation.
JENNY ( over P.A. ):
Fellow citizens,
we are facing
an emergency situation.
Please evacuate immediately.
( indistinct chattering )
MAN:
It's party time.
Please be patient.
The next ferry
will arrive shortly.
( indistinct chattering )
( alarm blaring )
What's that?
It sounds like the police.
ALL:
Huh?
Tory's out in the garden.
I have to go out
and get him.
Everyone,
evacuate immediately.
Right.
Why won't your
passport work?
This never happens.
Maybe, the system
is shutting down.
( all gasp )
Huh?
It stopped.
Rebooting.
( grunts )
MAN:
Hey!
( speaking indistinctly )
WOMAN 1: It's moving.
WOMAN 2: Where are we going?
( girl gasps )
WOMAN 3: Excuse me.
MAN: Watch it.
( screams )
Professor Lund.
Ah.
MEOWTH:
Oh, some vacation
this turned out to be.
JESSIE:
Whose bad idea was this?
JAMES:
Let's just say Meowth and I
were overruled.
JESSIE AND MEOWTH:
Huh?
Hey!
( suspenseful theme playing )
What's happening here?
Those things
are carrying people away.
Deoxys, why are you doing
this to us?
( Raybuaza howls )
Huh?
( roars )
The force field.
( dramatic theme playing )
COMPUTER:
Losing power.
All systems
will now shut down.
( roars )
( roaring )
( grunts )
Blastoise. Blas--
Blastoise.
( grunts )
BOTH:
You got it.
Hold on a sec.
It's multiplying.
What is that thing?
Deoxys.
You know its name?
You guys, come back.
ALL:
Huh?
( all gasp )
No, May, look out.
Hey, what do you want?
Blastoise,
use Hydro Pump. Go!
Blastoise!
Blastoise.
Put me down.
Blastoise! Blast!
Sid, no!
May, get in here.
Blaziken, use Flamethrower.
Blaze.
ASH:
Pikachu, Thunderbolt.
PIKACHU:
Pikachu!
Tory, is there
another way out?
Yeah, there is
an underground exit.
Can you show us?
Yes, follow me.
Everyone, let's go.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Blaze!
( screams )
Way to go, Rafe.
All in a day's work.
What do they want?
Let's hurry.
Come on, Brock, it's open.
Okay.
All right, Ash, Rafe,
we gotta go.
Pikachu.
Pika.
( grunts )
Blaze.
Guys, this way.
( panting )
Pika?
Pika!
( all grunt )
Pikachu,
use Thunderbolt now.
Pikachu!
Thanks, Pikachu.
Good Thunderbolt.
Ash, what are you doing?
Let's go.
This is the way
to get out of here.
Wonder where we are now.
It seems to be safe.
There you are.
TORY:
It's Yuko.
( Pokémon chattering )
( panting )
Munch.
Munch?
Munch. Munch.
Munch.
( wind gusting )
( Rayquaza howls )
( Rayquaza roars )
POLICEWOMAN:
Professor, take a look
at all of these people
shown here.
Their evacuation
hasn't been confirmed
at any
of the passport checkpoints.
I'm afraid that could mean
they're still stuck
in Larousse.
( grunts )
The entire town is enclosed
within a force field.
It's impossible for anyone
to come in or to leave.
All communication
with the outside
is jammed as well.
They've switched
to backup generators,
but all systems
are still down.
Even the Poké Ball
Management System
isn't functioning.
Yeah, it won't work.
How can we call out
our Pokémon?
Guess we can't.
Hey, Tory,
what did you call that thing?
Was it Deoxys?
Hmm-mm.
That's right.
A Pokémon from outer space.
What?
Four years ago,
a meteorite came down
and struck the North Pole.
And located inside of it
was a completely
unknown Pokémon.
It was Professor Lund
who gave that Pokémon
the name Deoxys.
( roaring )
But then almost
immediately,
Rayquaza appeared
from the ozone
and attacked Deoxys.
( roars )
Apparently,
Rayquaza was threatened
and thought Deoxys
was invading its territory.
Deoxys vanished deep
into the sea.
BROCK:
I don't get it. How could it be
the same Deoxys?
After getting beaten
by Rayquaza,
Deoxys must have slowly
been regenerating.
Regenerating?
That's right,
it has astounding
regenerative powers.
And that's
what Professor Lund and I
have been studying
all these years.
REBECCA:
It sounds more
like science fiction.
This is something
I'd love to research.
But I wonder if
it could somehow get in
through a crack in the wall.
Knock it off, Max.
Yeah, stop scaring us
right now.
( laughing ):
Just kidding.
There's no way it's coming in
through a crack.
( door opens )
What was that?
Come on, Blaziken.
Blaze. Blaze.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( clanging and rumbling )
Blaze.
Pika.
( both chattering )
Oh!
Pika!
Munch.
Hey, that's the Pokémon
that ate every bite
of our food.
Are you stuck in there,
Munchlax?
Let's see.
( grunting )
Our sandwiches.
Everything
but the peanut butter. Hmm.
And, of course,
that one was mine.
Hold on. Hold on.
Okay, please just don't come
any closer, you two.
Pika. Pikachu.
Munch.
( sighs )
I'm so hungry.
So am I.
Me too.
Mu--
Mu--?
Munchlax.
Really? I can have it?
Munch. Munch. Munch.
ALL: No, thanks.
Munch.
( all gasp and sigh )
BROCK:
We have to find food and water
right away.
Great. And I'll try and find out
where those people were taken.
Yuko, take care
of my sisters, please.
Of course,
but don't you worry about us.
You take care of yourselves.
RAFE:
We will.
ASH:
All right, let's go.
Munchlax.
( indistinct chattering )
( sighs )
I'm worried, Max.
I really hope
they're all okay.
Yeah, me too.
I wish they'd hurry
and come back.
( speaks indistinctly
)
Still no good.
Nothing's happening.
Yeah. It must be tied
into the town's system.
I can see the food
in there too.
We just need to figure out
a way to break in.
Pika. Pika.
Hmm?            Hmm?
Pikachu!
It worked.
Pikachu, great idea.
Pikachu.
Whoa, gotta catch them all.
Pika.
Pikachu. Pika?
Huh? What is it, Pikachu?
( all gasp )
Look out!
Run!
Pika!
Look out!
Plusle. Minun.
( both screaming )
ASH: Put me down!
BROCK: Let go!
( grunts )
Pikachu!
( all grunts )
No!
( whimpers )
( screaming )
Pika.
( gasps )
Here they all come, guys.
Pika.
Come on, Tory,
let's go.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Looks like they're all gone.
That was close.
Oh, Plusle.
It's all my fault.
I should've.
( sighs )
I'm sorry.
Pika. Pika. Pika.
Pikachu.
BROCK:
Ash,
look what I just found.
Precious water.
ASH: All right!
RAFE:
Okay, so that's where
they're holding everyone
captive.
I guess,
but what in the world for?
ROBOT:
Release immediately.
( weakened ):
Release immediate--
It let go.
But why?
( Rayquaza howls )
( all snoring )
Hmm, go back.
Let me just take
another look at that.
Sure.
Surskit. Surskit.
What is it? What's wrong?
Pika.
( object clatters )
Blaze?
( both scream )
Let's get out of here.
YOKU:
Yes, there's an underground
laboratory.
Let's go. Follow me.
MAX: Munchlax.
Munch?
Munch. Munch. Munch.
Try and stay calm.
Now go.
( dramatic theme playing )
We should be safe down here
for the time being.
RAFE: That's good.
BLAZE: Blaze. Blaze.
Pika.
ASH:
What's this?
YOKU:
The lab where we studied Deoxys
and its regeneration.
There were actually two
of them before.
Rayquaza defeated one
while the other Deoxys
was still dormant
inside of this meteorite.
TERESA:
So then you're saying that--
YOKU:
Yes. That crystal,
it's a part of Deoxys.
Part of--
What do you mean?
Pika.
( all gasp )
What?
Hey, Tory, it's your friend.
Pika.
Wait a second.
Then Tory's friend is--
Right. It's Deoxys.
( all gasp )
Huh?
That's it.
It all makes sense.
This is Tory's friend's
light pattern.
And this is the pattern
of the aurora
that covered Larousse.
It's the same.
Yeah, I think it might be
how they communicate.
Oh, I see.
So can you tell what it says?
TERESA:
Well, let's start
with the green pattern.
This one means friend.
And this one seems
to be asking,
"Where are you?"
So it's just looking
for its friend?
Pika.
YOKU:
Of course. Deoxys carried off
all those people and Pokémon
because they were interfering
while it searched
for its friend.
What?
Deoxys sees certain types
of electrical fields.
But it's not only
electrical devices
that give off those fields,
so do people and Pokémon,
and they were blocking
its vision.
That's why it's moving them
out of the way,
to find it.
( dramatic theme playing )
( gasps and sighs )
Please, Yuko, you've got
to help this Deoxys regenerate.
It's so sad.
It's been alone
all of this time.
You're right. Once Deoxys finds
its friend, it'll go back home.
Pikachu.
But the problem is,
the emergency power
we're running on now
isn't nearly enough necessary
to operate this device.
If it's electricity you want,
then I'm your guy.
I can get
the wind generators going.
Can we help?
Yes, we'll need everyone's help
to save those people
and Pokémon.
Let's start working
on a plan,
and then we'll go out
to where they're being held.
I'll zero in on it.
That's where they all are.
ASH:
Great. Let's go get them, guys.
ALL:
All right!
( suspenseful theme playing )
( all chattering )
( panting )
I'll never take an escalator
for granted again.
( grunts )
Deoxys, we're not your enemies.
We're your friends.
If you'll just trust us,
we can help you
find your friend. I promise.
Blaziken, use Flamethrower now.
Pikachu, Thunderbolt him.
Pikachu!
Metagross, use Reflector.
Meta!
TERESA:
Quick, now's our chance.
TORY:
This way.
Now, Overheat.
Blaze!
You okay?
We're fine, Ash.
Just go on.
Rafe can handle it.
Just don't let anything happen
to my sisters, Ash.
You can count on that.
Blaziken, Overheat!
Blaze.
( roars )
Rayquaza has broken through.
What have I done?
Blaze....
Relax, Blaziken.
Blaze.
( roars )
( all chattering )
Rayquaza.
Now what's that?
( roaring )
All right, now let's do it
just like we planned. Okay guys?
BROCK:
Got you.
TERESA:
We're with you, Ash.
Munch. Munch. Munch.
Munchlax.
Come on, there's no time for you
to go back for it.
Oh, Munchlax!
You ready?
Just about.
All we need
is the electricity.
But if we had that,
we wouldn't need to fix it.
What are they doing over there?
I'm hoping he pulls a sandwich
out of that box.
From your lips,
to my stomach.
ASH:
You guys,
we've come to help you.
Hey, Ash, we're up here.
You got Pikachu
and Plusle, right?
Yeah. We're all set.
Pika.
( Rayquaza roars )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( roars )
( growls )
ASH: Pikachu.
TORY: Plusle.
BOTH:
Thunderbolt, now.
SID:
There's your electricity.
( Pikachu screams )
That's good. Stop.
All right.
We're recharged.
Yeah!
All right.
( grunting ):
Ouch.
( both chattering )
( both scream )
You were great, Tory.
( heroic theme playing )
( laughs )
( roars )
( all panting )
Let's go.
Yeah.
( grunts )
That should do it.
Coming down!
( grunts )
( groans )
SID:
Hey, May, I'm coming for you.
Was that Sid?
BOTH:
Uh, and Rafe!
May!
( grunts )
Gross.
Metagross.
Audrey, Kathryn,
you okay?
KATHRYN: Uh-huh.
AUDREY: We're fine.
Where's Ash and the others?
They went back
to the laboratory.
Okay, are you ready
to get started on this?
( switches clicking )
Perfect, the power's
back on.
Yeah, those guys
pulled it off.
Mm-hmm.
( all grunting )
( all chattering )
Blaziken. Blaziken.
Metagross.
( all groaning )
My cramp's
getting a cramp.
We're always spinning
our wheels
but this is ridiculous.
Just pedal!
I'm set. Are you both ready
to use the laser?
Yes. I think
you should turn it on, Tory.
It is your friend after all,
so you should do it.
Hmm.
Here goes.
( dramatic theme playing )
Pika.
TORY:
Still no good.
Oh, no,
we're still 20 percent short
on energy.
Wow, we're so close.
Okay, Pikachu,
Plusle, Minun,
you know what to do.
Pika.
Pikachu!
( both shouting )
( upbeat theme playing )
Great idea,
we got just what we need.
It works.
All right.
( all shouting )
( glass shattering )
( all gasp )
( dramatic theme playing )
We did it!
Oh, Deoxys,
it's really you.
( chuckles )
Pika!
Deoxys, do you wanna go
find your friend now?
( both laugh )
Pika.
Pika!
ASH & TORY:
Whoa!
( roars )
( all gasping )
The force field's gone.
Just like that?
( roars )
( heroic theme playing )
( roaring )
( whimpers )
Pika.
( Rayquaza roars )
( both gasp )
Pika.
( mellow theme playing )
( both gasp )
Pika.
( both chattering )
( laughing ):
Pika.
( both gasp )
Pika!
( suspenseful theme playing )
Hey, knock it off!
Stop, Rayquaza.
Pika.
( roaring )
( roars )
Warning! Warning!
Warning!
Danger! Danger! Danger!
Evacuate! Evacuate!
What happened?
Security somehow started up.
Warning! Evacuate!
Warning!
( weakening ):
Evacuate.
Warning. E-vac-u-ate.
Somehow security
has gone on overdrive.
It won't shut down.
Yuko.
Professor Lund.
( roaring )
Everything's
totally out of control.
Ash, I'm scared.
Rayquaza. Deoxys.
Pika!
Whoa!
Plusle. Minun.
Pikachu.
Pika.
They almost hit us that time.
Let's try and get back
to Yuko.
Tory, can you hear me? Tory?
Daddy.
You must listen
to me very carefully.
As you can see, all the block
robots are malfunctioning.
The chief robot,
which controls
all other block robots,
should be near you.
We no longer have power
over that robot from the booth.
Understand?
So here's what you have to do.
And I need for you to be brave.
Tory, do you have
your passport?
You must present your passport
to the chief robot.
Then everything should unlock
but only
for a very brief moment.
That should allow us
just enough time
to regain control.
And shut down
the security system.
Block robots are surrounding
the battle tower
making any approach by us
impossible.
Son, the fate of our town
is in your hands.
I know we can count on you--
ROBOT:
Warning! Evacuate!
Warning!
( weakening ):
Eva--
( suspenseful theme playing )
Don't you worry, sir.
Pikachu and I
are gonna help Tory
save this town together.
Pika.
ASH:
We've gotta get to that tower.
Look at that.
Quick, let's go.
Okay. Just a little more.
ALL:
Whoa!
Munch, Munch, Munch.
Munchlax?
( all scream )
Snorlax.
A Snorlax. That's it.
Sorry.
Pika.
TORY:
Hey, Ash.
Tory, don't worry.
I'm okay.
I'll take care of this.
Pika.
Pikachu.
Pika!
Oh, wow, cool.
I'm right behind you.
( grunting )
Pika! Pika!
No!
Oh, no.
Pikachu.
TORY:
Ash!
Use my passport!
Throw it.
( grunts )
Pika.
Pikachu!
Pika, Pika. Pikachu.
This better work.
COMPUTER:
Passport has been verified.
Disengaging all locks.
I'm almost there.
Disengage.
( chimes )
It worked, guys.
( grunts )
Oh, no, Tory.
( heroic theme playing )
Deoxys.
( laughs )
Pika.
Pikachu.
( chuckles )
Pika! Pika!
( chuckling )
Pika. Pika.
( laughs )
Pika!
( roars )
SNORLAX:
Snorlax.
( all chuckling )
Tory.
Daddy.
( Tory laughs )
Tory.
Hi, Dad.
I'm so happy
you're safe.
But I'm only okay
because of my friends.
TORY:
Come on, guys. That tickles.
PIKACHU:
Pika.
( majestic theme playing )
Goodbye. I'll miss you.
I wonder where
they're going.
Yeah.
But now, wherever they go,
they'll always have each other.
Pikachu.
Hey, Pikachu?
I'm glad that you and I
will always have each other.
Pika. Pikachu.
( Bree Sharp's
"This Side of Paradise" plays )
I must have lost
20 pounds so far.
And you already lost
your mind.
And I'm losing
my patience,
so just shut up
and keep pedaling!
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la
La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ There's a place I know ♪
♪ It's always jumping ♪
♪ I'm thinking we should go
And leave our worries ♪
♪ You've got a friend in me ♪
♪ And I'll tell you something ♪
♪ This time
Could be extraordinary ♪
♪ When shadows fall
You're feeling small ♪
♪ It looks like walls
Are closing in ♪
♪ Don't be afraid
The dark will fade ♪
♪ Just take my hand
And look again ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ Is where I want to be ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ What you get
Is what you see ♪
♪ And I never thought
I'd see a place as nice ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la
La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ We're gonna take a ride ♪
♪ We're gonna
Catch that train ♪
♪ When your at my side
The world has hope ♪
♪ And as we pass on by ♪
♪ We all look the same ♪
♪ The clouds are high
The world is open ♪
♪ Forget about
The pain and doubt ♪
♪ Your happiness is overdue ♪
♪ I've been dreaming of ♪
♪ The skies above ♪
♪ Dancing through
The stars with you ♪
♪ Oh, take me to ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ Is where I want to be ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ What you get
Is what you see ♪
♪ And I never thought
I'll see a place as nice ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la
La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ I've been ♪
♪ Dreaming ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ I've been ♪
♪ Dreaming ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ Dreaming ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ There's a place I know ♪
♪ It's always jumping ♪
♪ I'm thinking we should go ♪
♪ And leave our worry ♪
♪ You've got a friend in me ♪
♪ And I'll tell you something ♪
♪ This time could be ♪
♪ Extraordinary ♪
♪ When shadow fall
You're feeling small ♪
♪ It looks like walls
Are closing in ♪
♪ Don't be afraid
The dark will fade ♪
♪ Just take my hand ♪
♪ And look again ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ Is where I want to be ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ What you get
Is what you see ♪
♪ And I never thought
I'd see a place as nice ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ We're gonna take a ride ♪
♪ We're gonna
Catch that train ♪
♪ When you're at my side ♪
♪ The world has opened ♪
♪ As we pass on by ♪
♪ We all look the same ♪
♪ The clouds are high ♪
♪ The world is open ♪
♪ Forget about
The pain and doubt ♪
♪ Your happiness is overdue ♪
♪ I've been dreaming of
Skies above ♪
♪ Dancing through ♪
♪ The stars with you ♪
♪ Oh, take me to ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ Is where I want to be ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ What you get
Is what you see ♪
♪ And I never thought
I'll see a place as nice ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ I've been ♪
♪ Dreaming ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ This side of paradise
I've been ♪
♪ Dreaming ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la
La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ This side of paradise ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪